[{"question":"Laboratory wattmeter are -","answers":{"a":"Induction type","b":"Moving iron type","c":"Electrostatic type","d":"Electro-dynamometer type"},"correctAnswer":"d"},
{"question":"The energy to supply power to the relay is provided by -","answers":{"a":"Current transformer","b":"Potential transformer","c":"Transmission line","d":"A&B"},"correctAnswer":"d"},
{"question":"The primary winding of a current transformer is connected in_____ with the line carrying the main current and the secondary winding is directly connected across______. -","answers":{"a":"Series, ammeter","b":"Parallel , voltmeter","c":"Parallel, ammeter","d":"Series, voltmeter"},"correctAnswer":"a"},
{"question":"In case Potential transformer, if the load on secondary winding increases then: -","answers":{"a":"Both the ratio error and phase angle increases","b":"The ratio angle decreases and power factor increases","c":"Both the ratio and power angle decreases","d":"Ratio increases and power factor decreases"},"correctAnswer":"a"},
{"question":"The ration error in current transformer is attributed to: -","answers":{"a":"Leakage flux","b":"Magnetizing component of no load current","c":"Power factor of primary","d":"Energy component of excitation current"},"correctAnswer":"b"},
{"question":"An industrial analyser is NOT suitable for measuring which of the following -","answers":{"a":"Power","b":"Current","c":"Resistance","d":"Power factor"},"correctAnswer":"c"},
{"question":"Electric motor is the device which converts electrical energy into ________energy. -","answers":{"a":"Light","b":"Heat","c":"Chemical","d":"Mechanical"},"correctAnswer":"d"},
{"question":"An electric motor uses the phenomena of -","answers":{"a":"Electromagnetic induction","b":"Heating effect","c":"Magnetic effect of current","d":"None of above"},"correctAnswer":"c"},
{"question":"In electric motor, force acts on only those arms whose length is _____ to magnetic field of magnet -","answers":{"a":"Perpendicular","b":"Parallel","c":"Inclined on 45Â°","d":"All of above"},"correctAnswer":"c"},
{"question":"Electric motor used in -","answers":{"a":"Fans","b":"Mixer and juice","c":"Washing machine","d":"All of above"},"correctAnswer":"d"}]